Guide to the Christopher Henley Papers, circa 1980s-2000s.
Henley, Christopher Papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Christopher Henley Papers, circa 1980s-2000s.
14-22-4265
Henley, Christopher Lee
21
Manuscripts, printed material, research materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of book material, talks/presentations and course material, including lecture outlines and notes, homework questions and answer keys.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University professor of physics; Christopher Henley started as a assistant professor of physics in 1989 and became a full professor in 2001. His research was in the theory of frustrated magnetism, both classical and quantum, interacting electron systems, quasicrystals, and biological physics. In biological physics, Henley led projects in pattern formation and mechanics, specifically a large project about the physical bases of left/right symmetry breaking in various animals including snails, in plants, or in assemblies of single cells.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of book material, talks/presentations and course material, including lecture outlines and notes, homework questions and answer keys.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Henley, Christopher Lee; Cornell University. Department of Physics.
Subjects:
Biophysics.; Crystallography.; Magnetism.; Neutron scattering.; Quasicrystals.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Physics 636 course and book material, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
- Physics 636 course and book material, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
- Physics 636 course and book material, 1997-1999 (Box 2)
- Physics 636 course and book material, 1999-2000, 2003, 2005 (Box 3)
- Physics 636 course and book material, 2005, 2007, 2009 (Box 4)
- Physics 636 course material, figures and transparencies, 2011-2012, undated (Box 5)
- Physics 636 course material, 1975-2006 (Box 6)
- Physics 636 course material, figures and transparencies, 1990-2012 (Box 7)
- Physics 636 course material, 1990's-2011 (Box 8)
- Physics 653 course material, 1973-2009 (Box 8)
- Physics 653 course material, 1992-2001 (Box 9)
- Physics 653 course material, 1989-2003 (Box 10)
- Physics 653 course material, 1985-2007 (Box 11)
- Physics 653 course material, 1989-2007 (Box 12)
- Physics course references, 2012-2013 (Box 12)
- Physics 653 course material, 1990-2008 (Box 13)
- Physics 562 and 454 course material, 1987-2014 (Box 14)
- Physics 454 course material, 1991-1997, undated (Box 15)
- Physics 2214 course material, 2000's (Box 16)
- Physics 12a course material, Undated (Box 16)
- Physics 122 course material, Undated (Box 16)
- Physics 683 course material, 2006 (Box 16)
- Left/right research, Date unknown (Box 16)
- Physics 654 course material, 2001-2014 (Box 17)
- Physics 653 course material, 1997-1998 (Box 17)
- Physics 636 course material, 1990's-2011 (Box 17)
- Teaching material, 1970's-1980's (Box 17)
- Book material, 1975-2003, undated (Box 17)
- Book material, 1993-2004 (Box 18)
- Book material, 1990-2012 (Box 19)
- Talk materials, research, and papers/articles, 1998-2010 (Box 20)
- USB drive of symposium, Date unknown (Box 20)
- Talk materials, research, theses, personal college coursework, and papers, 1976-2006 (Box 21)